Register of the Susan Weissman Radio Broadcast Interviews
Hoover Institution Archives
Susan Weissman Radio Broadcast Interviews
1986-2000
88042
Weissman, Susan, interviewer.
11 cassette boxes (4 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Sound recordings on compact sound cassettes relating to contemporary political, social and economic conditions throughout the world, and especially in the Soviet Union and its successor states, from a weekly radio program broadcast on radio station KPFK, Los Angeles.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research. The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1988 with additional increments through the year 2000.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
Susan (Suzi) Weissman, a Professor and Chair of Politics at Saint Mary's College of California, sits on the editorial boards of Critique and Against the Current. She is the author of Victor Serge: The Course Is Set on Hope (Verso, 2001); and edited Victor Serge: Russia Twenty Years After (Humanities, 1996), and The Ideas of Victor Serge (Critique Books, 1997), as well as many articles on the Soviet Union and Russia. Her research emphasis is on working class and left wing dissent. Weissman has hosted drive-time broadcast public affairs programs on KPFK radio of Los Angeles for more than two decades. During the years of turmoil and disintegration of the Soviet Union, she hosted many special programs and live broadcasts from participants. She began as host of "Portraits of USSR" and "Read All About It" later titled "The New World Disorder" before it morphed into "Beneath the Surface."
Source: Suzi Weissman (about) page, http://suziweissman.com/?q=about accessed 11 August 2010
Scope and Content of Collection
Sound recordings on compact sound cassettes relating to contemporary political, social, and economic conditions throughout the world, and especially in the Soviet Union and its successor states, from a weekly radio program broadcast on radio station KPFK, Los Angeles. The collection also includes program description lists for the years 1995-2000, and an article, which may be found in the last box.
Arrangement
The cassettes are organized chronologically. Sound recording date, title, and additional information in parentheses were selected from the cassette labels created by Weissman or her staff.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
World politics--20th century.; Former Soviet republics.; Soviet Union--Politics and government--1985-1991.; Russia--(Federation)--Politics and government--1991-; Phonotapes.; KPFK (Radio station: Los Angeles, Calif)
Collection Contents
- 1986
  - Richard Greeman on Victor Serge Part I, 10 April 1986 (Box 1)
  - U.S. Leftist Intellectuals of the 1930s, 24 April 1986 (Box 1)
  - M. Lowy on Latin America, 1 May 1986 (Box 1)
  - Richard Greeman on V. Serge Part II, 15 May 1986 (Box 1)
  - Paul Robeson Jr. on USSR Today, 19 June 1986 (Box 1)
  - Hillel Ticktin (H. Ticktin) on Chernobyl, 3 July 1986 (Box 1)
  - Mike Davis, Side B, 10 July 1986 (Box 1)
  - Burnett Bolloten, Side A, 17 July 1986 (Box 1)
  - Bolloten et al on the Civil War in Spain, 17 July 1986 (Box 1)
  - K. Shakiri on the Situation in Iran, 24 July 1986 (Box 1)
  - H. Ticktin on The Moscow Manifesto, 21 Aug. 1986 (Box 1)
  - John Amsden Econ, 18 September 1986 (Box 1)
  - State of French Socialism, 25 September 1986 (Box 1)
  - Alexander Amerisov, 2 October 1986 (Box 1)
  - Alexander Amerisov on Reykjavik, 16 October 1986 (Box 1)
  - Robert Conquest on the Ukraine Famine, 30 October 1986 (Box 1)
  - Tim Harding on Brazil, 13 November 1986 (Box 1)
  - R. Schoenman on Poland, 4 December 1986 (Box 1)
  - Tariq Ali on The Defeat of the British Miners Strike, 11 December 1986 (Box 1)
  - Alexander Amerisov on "Dissidents,", 23 December 1986 (Box 1)
- 1987
  - Alan Wald on Nicaragua, 1 January 1987 (Box 1)
  - Alec Nove on Soviet Economics, 15 January 1987 (Box 1)
  - Alexander Amerisov on "Reconstruction" under Gorbachev, 29 January 1987 (Box 1)
  - Weissman Reads an unpublished interview with USSR "left-winger,", 5 February 1987 (Box 1)
  - The Gorbachev Reforms, 19 February 1987 (Box 1)
  - Reading of Article on Glasnost, 5 March 1987 (Box 1)
  - Int. Carl Boggs on New Social Movements, 12 March 1987 (Box 1)
  - Alexander Amerisov on Glasnost Contradictions, 26 March 1987 (Box 1)
  - Americans Visit USSR, 2 April 1987 (Box 1)
  - Ralph Schoenman on Zionism, 9 April 1987 (Box 1)
  - Kostra Shakiri on Iran's Background, 23 April 1987 (Box 1)
  - Alexander Amerisov on Glasnost Contradictions, 11 June 1987 (Box 1)
  - Medvedev on Effects in USSR of Glasnost, 25 June 1987 (Box 1)
  - Prof M. Cox on Cold War Effects on USSR/U.S., 24 September 1987 (Box 1)
  - Glasnost and USSR intelligentsia article, 8 October 1987 (Box 1)
  - Alan Frankovitch on Latin America, 22 October 1987 (Box 1)
  - Alexander Amerisov on Glasnost, 29 October 1987 (Box 1)
  - USSR Article on Soviet Economy, 19 November 1987 (Box 1)
  - Alex Cockburn on a visit to USSR, 3 December 1987 (Box 1)
  - Mick Cox on the Impact of USSR/U.S. Summit, 17 December 1987 (Box 1)
- 1988
  - Interview: No Easy Solutions for Hungary, 8 January 1988 (Box 1)
  - Ralph Schoenman on Israel/Zionism, 14 January 1988 (Box 1)
  - V. Karpov et al: the Writers on Glasnost, 21 January 1988 (Box 1)
  - Richard Day on USSR Economy, etc., 11 February 1988 (Box 2)
  - Interview with Sieva Volkov, 18 February 1988 (Box 2)
  - Mike Davis/David Diaz on L.A. Problems, 25 February 1988 (Box 2)
  - B. Krawchenkoon National Question Today, 3 March 1988 (Box 2)
  - G. Liberidian on Armenian Dispute, 17 March 1988 (Box 2)
  - Mick Coxon The CIA and the Soviet Threat, 1 April 1988 (Box 2)
  - Mick Cox on CIA and Cold War Origins, 7 April 1988 (Box 2)
  - Alexander Amerisov on USSR Visit/Deportation, 12 May 1988 (Box 2)
  - Prof. Michael Cox on Summit Meeting, 26 May 1988 (Box 2)
  - Daniel Singer on Poland (orig. tape), 2 June 1988 (Box 2)
  - H. Ticktin from Glasgow on USSR Ills (2 tapes), 9 June 1988 (Box 2)
  - H. Ticktin Live from Glasgow on USSR Ills, Side A, 9 June 1988 (Box 2)
  - Kagarlitsky Interview Live from Moscow (2 tapes), 30 June 1988 (Box 2)
  - Barbara Dane, 14 July 1988 (Box 2)
  - Carl Boggs on USSR Today in Light of Perestroika and Glasnost, 7 July 1988 (Box 2)
  - Carl Boggs on USSR Today, 7 July 1988 (Box 2)
  - Alexander Amerisov on USSR Visit, Side A, Deportation, 28 July 1988 (Box 2)
  - Spanish Program, Side B, 28 July 1988 (Box 2)
  - Steven Ducat "Political Psychologist,", 18 August 1988 (Box 2)
  - H. Ticktin on Glasnost Impacts on USSR, East Europe, 25 August 1988 (Box 2)
  - David Mandel on Perestroika and Workers, 1 September 1988 (Box 2)
  - H. Ticktin on What Marxism Means, 8 September 1988 (Box 2)
  - USSR Book Fair at UCLA, 10 November 1988 (Box 2)
  - Ticktin and Cox on USSR Problems Today, 17 November 1988 (Box 2)
  - Z. Kowalewski on Poland's Problems, 1 December 1988 (Box 2)
  - Ralph Schoenman on the City College Los Angeles: One Year of the Intifada, 2 December 1988 (Box 2)
  - M. Cox on USSR-U.S. Relations Today, 8 December 1988 (Box 2)
  - Interview of Poet Irina Ratushinskaia, 15 December 1988 (Box 2)
  - H. Ticktin on British and USSR Economic Woes, 22 December 1988 (Box 2)
- 1989
  - G. Libaridian on Armenian Quake Politics, 5 January 1989 (Box 2)
  - Interview with Pierre Broué, from France, on Recent USSR Visit (by phone from Grenoble to L.A), 12 January 1989 (Box 2)
  - R. Schoenman on Intifada Struggle, 19 January 1989 (Box 2)
  - USSR Women Film Directors Interview, 26 January 1989 (Box 2)
  - Jan Kavan on Glasnost Impact on Czechs, 2 February 1989 (Box 2)
  - Tariq Ali on British Miners Strike (Loss and Thatcher's Economic Crackdown), 9 February 1989 (Box 2)
  - B. Rubin on Afghanistan Problems Today (as USSR Presence Departs), 16 February 1989 (Box 2)
  - Kagarlitsky Interview, Moscow, 23 March 1989 (Box 2)
  - M. Urban on Current USSR Elections, 30 March 1989 (Box 2)
  - Tim Harding on Cuba and Perestroika, 6 April 1989 (Box 2)
  - D. Singer on Perestroika Impact in Europe, 13 April 1989 (Box 2)
  - Rebroadcast of Program on Emma Goldman (interview with Alex Wexler), 20 April 1989 (Box 3)
  - Alexander Amerisov on Perestroika Today in USSR and Future Trends, 27 April 1989 (Box 3)
  - Infante and Bowlt on USSR Art in Glasnost Era, 4 May 1989 (Box 3)
  - Edward Said and Saul Friedländer on Intifada (on the Continued Conflict in Israel), 11 May 1989 (Box 3)
  - Weissman Reads Article on China by J. Petris, 18 May 1989 (Box 3)
  - Robert Scheer Speech on USSR Visit, 25 May 1989 (Box 3)
  - Richard Smith on China Economic Ills, Side A, 1 June 1989 (Box 3)
  - Portions of the "Wizard Show," Side B, 1 June 1989 (Box 3)
  - Nigel Harris on Dilemmas in China Today, 8 June 1989 (Box 3)
  - Mike Davis on Prisoners of American Dream, 15 June 1989 (Box 3)
  - Les Evans on China after the Massacre, 29 June 1989 (Box 3)
  - Schoenman/Shone on China Visit, 13 July 1989 (Box 3)
  - Daniel Singer from Paris on Poland and Europe Recent Events, 20 July 1989 (Box 3)
  - Weissman Reads D. Mandel on Perestroika and Workers, 3 August 1989 (Box 3)
  - Kagarlitsky in Moscow Interviewed on Miners' Strike. By telephone, 10 August 1989 (Box 3)
  - H. Ticktin on Polish and USSR Dilemmas Today, 17 August 1989 (Box 3)
  - H. Ticktin on Market No Economic Way Out, 31 August 1989 (Box 3)
  - Sam Farber on Cuba's Problems Today, 7 September 1989 (Box 3)
  - H. Ticktin on Meaning of "Market,", 14 September 1989 (Box 3)
  - Davist Ost on Whither Poland?, 21 September 1989 (Box 3)
  - James Petris on Third World Dilemmas, 28 September 1989 (Box 3)
  - G. Libaridian on Armenia Blockade Crisis, 5 October 1989 (Box 3)
  - D. Mandel on Miners' Strike Impact on Labor, 12 October 1989 (Box 3)
  - J. J. Nyomarkay on Eastern Europe Reforms. Germany, Hungary, Poland, on Eastern Europe Reforms. Germany, 19 October 1989 (Box 3)
  - V. Stratonovich Interview, USSR exchange professor, and John Collier, U.S. Student, on USSR Today, 9 November 1989 (Box 3)
  - Dr. R. Daniels on USSR: What Next?, 16 November 1989 (Box 3)
  - Ivan Szelenyi on Hungarian Elite: A Case Study in East European Reform, 30 November 1989 (Box 3)
  - B. Hirson on Whither South Africa?, 7 December 1989 (Box 3)
  - Karel Kovanda on Czechoslovakia Changes (Czech Students Spark New Czech Era as USSR Influence Wanes), 14 December 1989 (Box 3)
  - Prof. Samuel Beck on Tragedy in Romania as Troops Kill Thousands, 21 December 1989 (Box 3)
- 1990
  - S. Stankevich on Perestroika's Socialism, 11 January 1990 (Box 3)
  - Ronald Suny on Armenia-Azerbaijan Conflict, 18 January 1990 (Box 3)
  - USSR Disabled on History and Future, 25 January 1990 (Box 3)
  - H. Ticktin on Anti-Semitism in USSR, Side A, 22 February 1990 (Box 3)
  - Read All About It, Side B, 23 February 1990 (Box 3)
  - Kagarlitsky on Elections and USSR Trends, 15 March 1990 (Box 3)
  - New Left Review on USSR Changes, Side A, 22 March 1990 (Box 3)
  - Weissman Continues on Kagarlitsky 3/15 KPFK Interview, Side B, 23 March 1990 (Box 3)
  - Michael Urban on Lithuanian Syndrome, 29 March 1990 (Box 3)
  - Rafael Khazaryan on The Armenia Problem, 19 April 1990 (Box 3)
  - Pavel Campeano on Romania in 1990 after Ceausecu, 26 April 1990 (Box 3)
  - Yevgeny Yevtushenko on Interview, Reading, 3 May 1990 (Box 3)
  - B. Krawchenko on Ukraine and USSR Problems, 10 May 1990 (Box 3)
  - Alec Nove on USSR-U.S. Summit Perspectives (Policy Contradictions), 31 May 1990 (Box 3)
  - Boris Timoshenko on Rukh in Ukraine and USSR, 7 June 1990 (Box 3)
  - H. Ticktin on Economic Crisis Deepens, 16 August 1990 (Box 4)
  - M. Urban on "All Power to the Soviets,", 30 August 1990 (Box 4)
  - H. Ticktin on Gorbachev "Market" Economy, 13 September 1990 (Box 4)
  - US/USSR Press on 500-Day Economic Plan, Side A, 27 September 1990 (Box 4)
  - Read About It on The Real Causes of Cancer, Side B, 28 September 1990 (Box 4)
  - Prof. Prof. Nyomarkay, USC, on Impact of the New United Germany, 4 October 1990 (Box 4)
  - Ali Javadi on Iran's Problems in 1990s, Side A, 11 October 1990 (Box 4)
  - Ali Javadi on Iran's Dilemmas - 1990s, 11 October 1990 (Box 4)
  - Mark Cooper Reports on Visit to Chile, Pinochet's Sinister Shadow Is Alive, Side B, undated (Box 4)
  - Anthony Saidy on USSR Revisited, Side A, 18 October 1990 (Box 4)
  - Read All About It, Side B, 19 October 1990 (Box 4)
  - USSR "Market," A Very Rough Road (Because of technical difficulties this tape is not complete), 25 October 1990 (Box 4)
  - K. Malevich and USSR Abstract Art, 8 November 1990 (Box 4)
  - Dr. John Hatch of UCLA Department of History, and Vassily Shumov, Soviet Rock Musician on Soviet Pop Music in Glasnost Era), 15 November 1990 (Box 4)
  - H. Ticktin on Economic Paralysis in the USSR with, Michael Cox, Queen's Univ., N. Belfast, and Bob Arnot, Glasgow College of Economics), 29 November 1990 (Box 4)
  - Taras Chornovil and Roman Koshi on the Revolt in the Ukraine: What Next? (Translator: Bohdan Futala), 13 December 1990 (Box 4)
  - Sam Beck, Director, Field and International Studies, College of Human Ecology, Cornell University on the Romanian Revolt: Causes and Effects, 20 December 1990 (Box 4)
- 1991
  - Prof. Michael Urban of Auburn University on Lithuania: End of Perestroika? (), 17 January 1991 (Box 4)
  - James Petris, SUNY, Binghamton on Crisis in Eastern Europe (Article by James Petris, "Eastern Europe: Restoration and Crisis"), 24 January 1991 (Box 4)
  - Ticktin on Gorbachev's Crises, 7 February 1991 (Box 4)
  - Michael Cox and James Petris on USSR and the Gulf, 14 February 1991 (Box 4)
  - B. Krawchenko on the Ukraine in Turmoil, 25 April 1991 (Box 4)
  - Mandel USC Speech "New World Order,", 2 May 1991 (Box 4)
  - Marianne Gabriel on Juvenile Justice and Other Aspects of Perestroika Life, 16 May 1991 (Box 4)
  - Read All About It: James Petris Article "The Gulf War: The Meaning of the New World Order,", 17 May 1991 (Box 4)
  - David Mendel on the USSR Economic Crisis, Miners' Strike Dilemma, 23 May 1991 (Box 4)
  - The Real Costs of Chernobyl (article from weekly edition of the Washington Post), 30 May 1991 (Box 4)
  - The Novocherkassk Riot of 1962 (David Mandel visited the USSR and interviewed Pyotr Siuda, a key participant in the riot at Novocherkassk in 1962. Weissman reads opening part of the interview about workers' suppression in immediate post-Stalin era in which Stalinist crimes continued), 6 June 1991 (Box 4)
  - H. Ticktin on the Meaning of Yeltsin Victory and Its Effect, Soviet Economy Dilemmas, 13 June 1991 (Box 4)
  - Yugoslavia: Complications of Past and of the Future (Professor Ellen Commiso, University of California San Diego), 27 June 1991 (Box 4)
  - Sam Farber: USSR Before Stalinism (Farber, political science teacher, Brooklyn College, on his new book), 11 July 1991 (Box 4)
  - 40 Years a Stalinist Prisoner (Yuri Shukhevych, son of Ukrainian general; Yuri was jailed at age 15 and held 40 years in the Gulag), 18 July 1991 (Box 4)
  - Market Economic Fallacies (Ticktin, University of Glasgow, returns to USSR after 12 years, discusses changes, impossibility of making western "market" system work in near future, if at all), 8 August 1991 (Box 4)
  - Post Cold War Marxism: An Analysis (Moshe Machover, an Israeli Marxist, and H. Ticktin, University of Glasgow, analyze role of Marxism in post Cold War era), 15 August 1991 (Box 4)
  - USSR Coup Special Program, Part I Side A (A three hour program on the USSR coup recorded on two tapes. Those interviewed included Alec Nove, Stephen White, Michael Cox, and Sam Farber), 19 August 1991 (Box 4)
  - USSR Coup Special Program, Part II Side B, 19 August 1991 (Box 4)
  - USSR Coup Special Program, Part III Side A, 19 August 1991 (Box 4)
  - USSR Coup Special Program, Part IV Side B, 19 August 1991 (Box 4)
  - H. Ticktin: The Coup and USSR Future, 22 August 1991 (Box 4)
  - The USSR Coup: A Post Mortem (Prof. Alec Nove, University of Glasgow, Stephen White, University of Glasgow, and Michael Cox, Queens University Dept. of Politics, Belfast, N. Ireland), 23 August 1991 (Box 4)
  - Cuba in Crisis after Glasnost (Marc Cooper on the continuing crisis in Cuba, in the light of Glasnost and the coup in the USSR), 29 August 1991 (Box 4)
  - Boris Kagarlitsky on the Real Meaning of USSR Coup (Kagarlitsky, in Moscow, is interviewed by telephone. He gives his inside analysis of the coup with many facets apparently overlooked by TV and print media), 5 September 1991 (Box 4)
  - Michael Urban an Eye-Witness of the Coup (Urban, associate professor of political science at UC Santa Cruz, arrived in Moscow just as the coup got underway), 12 September 1991 (Box 4)
  - USSR's Georgia: Then and Now (Dr. Jill Schneiderman, Asst. Professor of Geology, Pomona College, on her recent trip to USSR's Georgia. Impact on Perestroika and coup noted), 26 September 1991 (Box 4)
  - N. Hollander Interviews Weissman on the USSR past and future, 27 September 1991 (Box 4)
  - Interview with Alexandra Yakovleva (Yakovleva, who is on editorial staff of bi-lingual publication "Inward Path" by telephone with interpreter), 3 October 1991 (Box 4)
  - Gerry Foley on the Post-coup National Problems of the USSR in light of the past and the prognosis for the future, 10 October 1991 (Box 4)
  - Robin Blackburn on USSR Problems (Blackburn, editor of New Left Review of London, and head of Verso Books, discusses post-Perestroika, post-coup USSR problems, especially publishing), 17 October 1991 (Box 5)
  - Iran CP Member on CP Future, Nationalism (Mansour Hekat, a member of the communist party of Iran, who lives in exile, gives his predictions on the future of social-democracy, socialist movements, communism and the future of nationalism), 24 October 1991 (Box 5)
  - The Coup Next Time(Weissman reads an article, The Coup Next Time, by the American free-lance journalist Vladamir Klimenko printed in the American magazine Mother Jones), 9 November 1991 (Box 5)
  - Economic Enigmas in Post-Glasnost USSR (Dr. Robert Arnat, Glasgow Polytechnic, states that the Latinization of the now broken-up USSR is not likely because of workers solidarity against "market" reforms), 5 December 1991 (Box 5)
  - Disparate Politics in USSR (Professor Michael Urban, Dept. of Soviet Politics, University of California at Santa Cruz, discusses his recent trips to the USSR), 12 December 1991 (Box 5)
  - Balkan Strife: Post-Coup USSR Model? (Weissman interviews Judith Gabriel, KPFK News director, following her journey to Yugoslavia and the Balkan War Area), 19 December 1991 (Box 5)
  - Director Andrei Konchalovskii on His New Film "Inner Circle" (Weissman discusses the new film on life in the USSR under Stalin), 26 December 1991 (Box 5)
- 1992
  - The Ukraine Reorganizes (Weissman interviews Bohdan Krawchenko, Director, Canadian Institute of Ukrainian Studies, University of Alberta, Edmonton, and current resident advisor to independent new government of Ukraine at Kiev), 2 January 1992 (Box 5)
  - Problems of Dissident Republics (Dr. Ronald Suny, Department of Armenian Studies, University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, elaborates on the difficulties in Georgia, the Caucacus, and Central Asia Republics who have not joined the commonwealth), 9 January 1992 (Box 5)
  - Three Articles on End of Stalinism (Weissman reads three articles: H. Ticktin, "The End of Stalinism Is the Beginning of Marxism" (unpublished article), and Kenneth Cloke: "From Marx to Stalin" a (draft article) and a book review by David Levy of Looking Forward), 23 January 1992 (Box 5)
  - Ukraine in Transition (Weissman interviews Hennadii Udovenko, Permanent representative of the Ukraine to the United Nations, and a deputy in the Ukrainian government, on the transition of Ukraine to a market economy and to independence from Moscow), 6 February 1992 (Box 5)
  - An American Engineer in Stalin's USSR, memoirs of the engineer Zara Witkin (Weissman discusses this book, covering 1932-1934, with Michael Gelb, Dept. of History at Franklin and Marshall College, Lancaster, PA., who "discovered" the book at the Hoover Institution), 13 February 1992 (Box 5)
  - Post-Columbus U.S. Multiculturalism (William Bollinger, Latin-American Studies Department, California State University at Los Angeles and Research Program Director, discusses influence of Latin America on U.S. multiculturalism), 20 February 1992 (Box 5)
  - International Trotskyism 1929-1985 Reviewed (Emeritus professor Robert J. Alexander of Rutgers University is interviewed by Weissman. They discuss Trotskyism's origin and its continued persistence throughout the world), 12 March 1992 (Box 5)
  - Did Religion Win the Cold War? (Weissman interviews Michael Cox, professor of economics, Queen's College, Belfast, Northern Ireland on whether Ronald Reagan "...won the Cold War..." as some pundits claim), 19 March 1992 (Box 5)
  - Economic Chaos in Ex-USSR (Weissman interviews H. Ticktin, University of Glasgow, on his new book on the economic and social chaos in the former USSR), 2 April 1992 (Box 5)
  - USSR Post-Coup Problems (In a wide-ranging interview Weissman discusses USSR post-coup problems with Boris Kagarlitsky, deputy of the Moscow City Council (Soviet) and key member of the Organizing Committee of the Party of Labor and Veteran Organizer of Independent Left), 9 April 1992 (Box 5)
  - Nationalist and Ethnic Strife: East and West (Weissman interviews Bogdan Denitch, professor of sociology at Queen's College, and the Graduate School of City University of New York, and vice-chairman of Democratic Socialists of America. Nationalist tendencies in Eastern Europe and in western countries are discussed, as well as ethnic strife), 7 May 1992 (Box 5)
  - Post-Coup Ukraine Faces Future (Weissman interviews Ivan Drach, co-chair of the Rukh Movement in the Ukraine, and a well-known poet, on the past, present, and future of the Ukraine. Translator: Bogdan Futala), 14 May 1992 (Box 5)
  - Whither Socialism After Stalinism? (Weissman speaking at a colloquium "Whither Socialism After Stalinism?" May 20, 1992, at the California State University at Los Angeles), 5 June 1992 (Box 5)
  - The Ascent of Conformity (Clare Spark and Weissman discuss the degeneration of free speech and the rise of conformity in the western world), 2 July 1992 (Box 5)
  - Talks on the Future of Socialism (Weissman reads papers by Neil Garsten and Trevor Cambell from the conference "The Future of Socialism" held May 29, 1992, at California State University at Los Angeles), 9 July 1992 (Box 5)
  - Siberian Reflections (Weissman interviews H. Ticktin, on the Novosibirsk Conference on the demise of Stalinism), 16 July 1992 (Box 5)
  - Yugoslavia: A Legacy of Terror (Weissman interviews Professor Ellen Commisso, University of California at San Diego (La Jolla) on the terror in what was Yugoslavia), 13 August 1992 (Box 5)